<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>On ML &amp; SE on William Bonvini&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://williambonvini.netlify.app/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in On ML &amp; SE on William Bonvini&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://williambonvini.netlify.app/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Topic Modeling with LDA</title>
      <link>https://williambonvini.netlify.app/blog/lda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://williambonvini.netlify.app/blog/lda/</guid>
      <description>Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA) is one of the most popular topic modeling techniques, even though the original paper has been published back in 2003. Topic modeling is a natural language processing technique that aims to automatically identify the underlying themes or topics in a collection of text documents. LDA produces two output
a probability distribution on words to represent topics a probability distribution on topics to summarize documents So imagine you have the following set of sentences (a sentence is just a very short document):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://williambonvini.netlify.app/blog/intro_to_rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://williambonvini.netlify.app/blog/intro_to_rl/</guid>
      <description>High Level Overview An example of reinforcement learning: the agent learns optimally to backflip. Source: Composing Value Functions in Reinforcement Learning. In this blogpost we will introduce the most important concepts in Reinforcement learning and provide some real world examples, to show you how and when it is currently being used.
This series is based on the lectures that DeepMind held for UCL in 2020, they are freely available at this YouTube link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write better documentation with Sphinx</title>
      <link>https://williambonvini.netlify.app/blog/sphinx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://williambonvini.netlify.app/blog/sphinx/</guid>
      <description>topic OS required modules Generate Sphinx documentation for a Python project with the ReadTheDocs theme. Windows venv High Level Overview Suppose that you have written a Python library and you want to share it with your colleagues. One of the most important things to do is to write a clear documentation. This tutorial will help you in achieving just that.
Our sample project&amp;rsquo;s structure will look like this
my_library | |---my_module.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
